<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WeedWise</string>
    <string name="open_nav">Open Drawer</string>
    <string name="close_nav">Close Drawer</string>
    <!-- TODO: Sedges weeds-->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment"></string>

    <string name="predict">predict</string>
    <string name="camera">Camera</string>

    <string name="reminder">In capturing an image, zoom in and center the flower or leaves of the weed. Avoid multiple species in the frame. Retake blurry and dark images.</string>
    <string name="disclaimer">DISCLAIMER: The image recognition feature is a test functionality and can only recognize 7 weed species. It will be improved in the succeeding versions.</string>

    <!-- Grasses -->
    <string name="char_colona">Stems usually grow flat on top of the soil surface, while the uppermost portions grow in an upward position (ascending). Most stems are purple or reddish. Spikelets are ovate to broad ovate, closely crowded in four rows along one side of the branch, nearly sessile, sometimes with an awn measuring less than 1mm.</string>
    <string name="imp_colona" formatted="false">E. colona is a C4 weed. One plant can produce 3,000 to 6,000 seeds. Control of this weed by hand weeding is difficult due to the close resemblances of its young seedlings to rice at early stages. Its full competition at ratios of 4:1 and 8:1 (weed: rice) reduces the yield of rice by 86% and 93%, respectively. The weed can also act as an alternate host to other pests such as Sarocladium oryzae, causing sheath rot of rice, rice bug, and rice black bug.</string>

    <string name="char_repens"> stem is erect and rooting at the hairless nodes. Leaves are linear-lanceolate, flat, and slightly hairy. Inflorescence has open panicle, slender and erect branches, oval to elliptic spikelets, and slender stalks. </string>
    <string name="imp_repens">Panicum repens, or torpedo grass, poses a significant challenge in rice cultivation due to its aggressive growth. It competes with rice plants for essential resources, leading to reduced yield and increased production costs. Additionally, its dense growth can hinder harvesting and impact rice quality, making effective weed management crucial for successful rice farming.</string>

    <string name="char_mutica">Brachiaria mutica, also known as para grass, can be identified by its distinctive characteristics. It is a perennial grass with wide, flat leaves and a creeping growth habit, often forming dense mats. The grass typically reaches a height of 1-2 meters and has a hollow stem with nodes. Its inflorescence consists of racemes with spikelets arranged in pairs.</string>
    <string name="imp_mutica">Brachiaria mutica can have a detrimental impact on rice cultivation. This invasive grass often competes with rice plants for vital resources, including water, sunlight, and nutrients. Its rapid growth and dense mats can smother young rice seedlings, reducing their chances of survival and growth. As a result, it can lead to reduced rice yields and economic losses for rice farmers. Effective weed control measures are essential to mitigate the impact of Brachiaria mutica in rice fields and maintain healthy and productive rice crops.</string>

    <string name="char_chinesis">slender, tufted, and can grow up to 120 cm tall. Its leaves are linear, flat, thin, membranous, and sometimes reddish or purplish. Its inflorescence has narrowly ovate panicles consisting of 2-7 spikelets</string>
    <string name="imp_chinesis">L. chinensis is a C4 weed and can produce 27,000 seeds per plant. It can reduce yield of rice by as much as 48% when allowed to compete at 16 plants/m2 . It is also an alternate host of other rice pests such as the green and zigzag leaf hoppers.</string>

    <string name="char_ciliaris">a creeping grass that has smooth, flattened stems. Basal parts of the stems are more or less lying on the ground while the upper stems are ascending. It has thin and narrow-lanceolate leaves; prominent, and membranous ligules that are clasping the stem. Inflorescence is composed of 3-6 pseudo-spikes digitally arranged as pseudo whorls at the apical portion.</string>
    <string name="imp_ciliaris">D. ciliaris is a C4 weed. A single plant can produce an average of 1,700 seeds. It reduces yield of rice by as much as 62%.</string>

    <string name="char_conjagatum">Stems are long-creeping, reddish-purple, have flattened runners, and hairy nodes. Leaves are flat, linear-lanceolate, hairy at the blades and sheaths. Leaf sheaths are flat, membranous, and with a collar of fine hairs below the blade. Ligules are membranous, truncate, and fringed with a ring of hairs at the back. Inflorescences have obtuse spikelets and two terminal spike-like slender branches.</string>
    <string name="imp_conjagatum" formatted="false">Paspalum conjugatum, commonly known as Hilo grass, exhibits distinctive characteristics and consequences for rice cultivation in the Philippines. It is notable for its prolific seed production, with each plant capable of yielding a substantial number of seeds. The control of Paspalum conjugatum through manual weeding is a formidable challenge, primarily due to its vigorous growth and resilience. When competing with rice crops, particularly at ratios of 4:1 and 8:1 (weed to rice), this weed can lead to significant reductions in rice yields, with decreases reaching 86% and 93%, respectively. Moreover, Paspalum conjugatum has the potential to act as a host for rice pathogens, such as Sarocladium oryzae, which can contribute to the spread of diseases like sheath rot in rice. Additionally, it can create conducive conditions for other pests, including rice bugs and rice black bugs, further complicating rice cultivation in the region.</string>

    <string name="char_dactylon"> stems are branching, spreading on the ground, and rooting at the nodes; leaves are covered with long white hairs around the ligules; spikes are terminal and finger-like; and seed heads consist of 3 to 7 finger-like spikes measuring 4 cm long. C. dactylon can be easily differentiated from Panicum repens and Paspalum distichum through its 2-3 leaves that grow on each node on extended runners.</string>
    <string name="imp_dactylon">C. dactylon is a C4 weed. It is an alternate host of disease-causing pathogens such as Bipolaris oryzae and Rhizoctonia solani. It can produce up to 230 seeds per panicle.</string>

    <string name="char_hexandra">stems are ascending or sub erect and rooting at the nodes while leaves are linear-lanceolate, acuminate with tiny backward-pointing spines at the back of midribs. Inflorescences have slender and sub-erect branches; and oblong spikelets.</string>
    <string name="imp_hexandra">Leersia hexandra, commonly known as ricefield ricegrass, can have a negative impact on rice cultivation. This weedy grass competes with rice plants for essential resources like sunlight, water, and nutrients, which can result in reduced rice yields. Managing L. hexandra is vital in rice fields to prevent crop yield losses and maintain the health and productivity of rice crops.</string>

    <string name="char_eleusine_indica">E. indica has a prostrate to ascending growth habit. Stems are flat, whitish at the base and pale green toward the upper part, and smooth or with long hairs on the edges. Leaves have sheaths that are flat and moderately hairy at the collar; leaf blades are flat, linear-lanceolate, and hairy on the upper surface; ligule is membranous; long hairs at the junction of blades and sheaths. No auricles; inflorescences are digitate with terminal whorls consisting of 3 to 6 spikes.</string>
    <string name="imp_eleusine_indica">E. indica is a C4 weed that can produce 50,000 seeds per plant on average. Its seeds are easily spread when eaten by animals. Its competitive ability against rice has yet to be reported. It is an alternative host to disease-causing organisms of rice, such as Rhizoctonia solani, Pyricularia oryzae, and Sarocladium oryzae, which cause sheath blight, blast, and sheath rot, respectively.</string>

    <string name="char_rogusom">Ischaemum rugosum, commonly known as rugose ischaemum, can be recognized by its distinct characteristics. It is a perennial grass with a tufted growth habit, typically reaching heights of 30-100 cm. The grass blades are long and narrow, often with a rough or "rugose" texture, and the stem nodes are often densely covered in hairs. Its inflorescence consists of slender spikes bearing spikelets.</string>
    <string name="imp_rogusom">Ischaemum rugosum can pose challenges to rice cultivation. This invasive grass competes with rice plants for essential resources like sunlight, water, and nutrients, which can result in reduced rice yields. Its dense growth and tufted habit can impede the development of rice crops, making effective weed management critical for maintaining healthy and productive rice fields. Weed control measures are often necessary to minimize the impact of Ischaemum rugosum on rice farming.</string>
    <!-- Sedges -->
    <string name="char_acuta" formatted="false">Eleocharis acuta, commonly known as spikerush, is characterized by its slender, cylindrical stems, typically reaching heights of 30-90 cm, and inconspicuous basal leaves that are often reduced to bladeless sheaths. The plant produces small, clustered flowers in a terminal spike. Its ability to reproduce through rhizomes allows it to form dense colonies.</string>
    <string name="imp_acuta" formatted="false">In rice fields, Eleocharis acuta can have significant impacts. It competes with rice for essential resources, such as nutrients, water, and light, potentially reducing rice yields. The dense growth of spikerush can obstruct water flow within rice fields and irrigation channels, leading to drainage problems and uneven water distribution. It also provides a habitat for pests and diseases, increasing pest pressure and interfering with the rice harvesting process. However, it can help stabilize soil and prevent erosion. Effective management strategies are necessary to balance control and ecological preservation in affected rice fields.</string>

    <string name="char_cyperus">Cyperus brevifolius, also known as shortleaf flatsedge, is recognized by its unique characteristics. It features short, narrow leaves, triangular stems reaching heights of 30-70 cm, and distinctive inflorescences with densely packed spikelets. The seed head contains reddish-brown seeds. This weed prefers wet environments like pond edges and spreads through rhizomes. These traits help distinguish Cyperus brevifolius from other plants, particularly within the Cyperus genus, though variations may occur based on growth stage and environmental conditions.</string>
    <string name="imp_cyperus" formatted="false">Cyperus brevifolius, also known as shortleaf flatsedge, can have significant implications for rice cultivation. This weed competes with rice plants for essential resources such as sunlight, water, and nutrients, potentially leading to decreased rice yields. Effective control and management strategies are essential to minimize the impact of Cyperus brevifolius on rice production. Additionally, the weeds presence can result in increased labor and operational costs for farmers, as they may need to implement measures to address its growth and prevent yield reductions. This underscores the importance of integrated weed management practices in rice fields to ensure optimal crop productivity while addressing the challenges posed by Cyperus brevifolius.</string>

    <string name="char_iria">Its stems are smooth and triangular; linear-lanceolate leaves; umbel-shaped inflorescence; and numerous, spreading, erect spikelets that are yellow to yellow-brown.</string>
    <string name="imp_iria" formatted="false">C. iria is a C4 weed. It can establish quickly in the field soon after rice plants are transplanted or direct-seeded. One plant can produce 3,000 seeds. When not controlled, it can reduce the yield of rice by as much as 40%. It can also act as an alternate host to other rice pests, such as green leafhoppers, and plant pathogenic microorganisms such as Pyricularia oryzae, Rhizoctonia solani, and Sarocladium oryzae, causing rice blast, sheath blight, and sheath rot diseases, respectively.</string>

    <string name="char_difformis">can grow as tall as 75 cm. It has stems that are pale green and sharply 3-angled at the top; shorter leaves than the stems; umbellate inflorescence that is simple or compound; and numerous spikelets that are globose</string>
    <string name="imp_difformis">C. difformis is a C3weed. One plant can produce 50,000 seeds with 60% germination. It can complete its life cycle within 30 days and spreads rapidly to become a dominant weed in a ricefield where moisture level is fluctuating. When left uncontrolled, it can reduce yield of rice byas much as 43%.</string>

    <string name="char_milicea">erect with flattened stems that bear 2-4 unequal bracts that are shorter than the inflorescence. Leaves are linear, flat, soft, and overlapping in two rows. Spikelets are numerous, globose to ovoid in shape, and brown to brown orange.</string>
    <string name="imp_milicea">F. miliacea, a C4 weed, is a prolific seed producer. A single plant can produce more than 40,000 seeds.</string>

    <string name="char_juncoides"> stems are erect and slender. Leaves degenerate to become sheath-like and cover the base of the stems. Fruits are brown to black when mature and broadly elliptical.</string>
    <string name="imp_juncoides">Scirpus juncoides, commonly known as soft rush, can impact rice fields both positively and negatively. It contributes to soil stabilization, wildlife habitat, and water quality improvement, but it can also compete with rice for resources, obstruct water flow, and create pest habitat. Effective management practices are essential to balance its presence in rice fields and ensure sustainable rice cultivation.</string>

    <string name="char_mucronatus">Scirpus mucronatus, also known as needle spike rush, is characterized by its slender, grass-like stems with triangular cross-sections and sharp, needle-like tips on its spikelets.</string>
    <string name="imp_mucronatus">Scirpus mucronatus can positively impact rice fields by stabilizing soil and reducing erosion risk. However, it can compete with rice for resources, obstruct water flow, and necessitate careful management to balance its presence for productive rice cultivation.</string>

    <string name="char_rotundos">erect with smooth unbranched three-sided stem, dark green leaves, and flowers in red-brown spikelets. It has extensive underground parts called the basal bulb, rhizomes, tubers, and roots which permit rapid production of multiple young sprouts in the soil. </string>
    <string name="imp_rotundos">C. rotundus is a C4 plant and is considered as the world’s worst weed. It is a problem due to its prolific behavior in the soil, persistence in harsh environments, and infestations in many crops. In earlier years, it used to be dominant only in upland rice areas in the Philippines but has adapted and infested irrigated and rainfed lowlands as well. Its full competition with upland rice plants reduces rice yield by 42%. Its effects on yields of irrigated and rainfed lowland rice plants, however, are still unknown.</string>

    <string name="char_schoenoides">Fimbristylis schoenoides, commonly known as slender fimbry, is a grass-like perennial plant with slender, wiry stems that can reach heights of up to 70 cm. Its leaves are typically reduced to bladeless sheaths, and it produces inconspicuous flowers in spikelets at the ends of its stems. Slender fimbry is commonly found in wetland environments, such as marshes, swamps, and the margins of ponds and streams, and it prefers soils that are wet or waterlogged.</string>
    <string name="imp_schoenoides">Fimbristylis schoenoides plays a role in wetland ecosystems by providing habitat and forage for wildlife, including insects and waterfowl, contributing to local biodiversity. Its root system helps stabilize soil and prevent erosion, which is crucial in wetland environments. Additionally, the plant aids in improving water quality by filtering pollutants and excess nutrients from the water, promoting a healthier aquatic ecosystem. In rice fields, its presence may signify waterlogged or poorly drained conditions, necessitating effective water management and drainage practices for optimal rice cultivation while minimizing potential adverse effects of excessive moisture.</string>

    <string name="char_fuirena">Fuirena umbellata, or umbrella sedge, is a wetland plant known for its slender, grass-like stems, umbrella-shaped clusters of small, inconspicuous flowers, and its preference for consistently wet or waterlogged soils.</string>
    <string name="imp_fuirena">While not a major threat to rice cultivation, the presence of Fuirena umbellata may indicate waterlogged conditions in rice fields. Excessive moisture can hinder rice growth, root development, and nutrient uptake, potentially affecting rice yields. Effective water management and drainage practices are crucial to optimize rice cultivation and mitigate the effects of excessive moisture.</string>
    <!-- Broadleaves -->
    <string name="char_indica"> with multiple pairs of leaflets. It is a creeping or sprawling perennial herb, typically found in wetland and marshy areas.</string>
    <string name="imp_indica">Aeschynomene indica, while not always considered a weed, can have a mixed impact on rice cultivation. In some cases, it may be planted alongside rice as a green manure or cover crop because it fixes nitrogen in the soil, benefiting rice growth. However, in high-density infestations, it can compete with rice for resources and reduce rice yield. Effective management strategies are needed to balance its potential benefits and drawbacks in rice fields.</string>

    <string name="char_alternifolius">Cyperus alternifolius, known as the umbrella plant, is characterized by its distinctive umbrella-like leaf arrangement. It thrives in wet or waterlogged soils and is often grown in aquatic gardens or as an ornamental plant. The plant has grass-like, erect stems and is typically found near water bodies.</string>
    <string name="imp_alternifolius">Although Cyperus alternifolius is not typically associated with rice fields, it can be invasive in natural aquatic environments. In this context, it could affect water management in rice fields if it establishes itself in waterways, potentially interfering with the controlled flooding and draining of fields.</string>

    <string name="char_coccinea">Red Ammannia stands out due to its reddish stems and leaves, which add a burst of color to wetland and aquatic landscapes. The plant is often found in waterlogged soils and is adapted to thrive in these conditions.</string>
    <string name="imp_coccinea">Red Ammannia is not a direct competitor with rice. However, its presence in rice fields can impact water flow and create an environment conducive to pests and diseases, especially in cases where it becomes too abundant.</string>

    <string name="char_vaginalis">Monochoria vaginalis is characterized by its heart-shaped leaves and can be recognized by its small blue to purple flowers. It is commonly found in wetlands and other waterlogged areas.</string>
    <string name="imp_vaginalis">In rice fields, Monochoria vaginalis can obstruct water flow, potentially leading to waterlogging issues. This, in turn, may reduce rice yields. Effective management practices are crucial to control its spread and minimize its impact.</string>

    <string name="char_ipomea">An aquatic weed that has slender, smooth, and creeping stems. It spreads on the ground or floats on water. Stems are hollow and rooting at the nodes. Leaves are alternately arranged with morphological variations in shapes. Flowers are funnel-shaped and are white to purple.</string>
    <string name="imp_ipomea" formatted="false">How the weed reduces the yield of rice has yet to be reported; it is an alternate host of golden apple snails in the absence of rice plants.</string>

    <string name="char_prostrata">Eclipta prostrata is a small herbaceous plant known for its daisy-like flower heads with white ray florets. It is adaptable to a range of habitats, including wet or damp locations.</string>
    <string name="imp_prostrata">Eclipta prostrata is not a significant threat to rice cultivation. It can coexist with rice without causing substantial harm, and its impact on rice fields is generally limited.</string>

    <string name="char_octovalvis">Ludwigia octovalvis is known for its oval-shaped leaves and yellow, showy flowers. It is commonly found in wetlands and along the edges of ponds and water bodies.</string>
    <string name="imp_octovalvis">In rice fields, Ludwigia octovalvis can be a nuisance, as it competes with rice for vital resources such as light, water, and nutrients. This competition may lead to a reduction in rice yields if left uncontrolled.</string>

    <string name="char_niruri"> Phyllanthus niruri is a small herbaceous plant that produces tiny, capsule-like fruits containing seeds. It is often found in various habitats, including moist and tropical regions.</string>
    <string name="imp_niruri">While Phyllanthus niruri may grow in rice fields, it is not typically a major threat to rice cultivation. Its impact on rice is generally limited, and it coexists with rice without causing significant harm.</string>

    <string name="char_crassipes">Water Hyacinth is easily recognizable by its floating, glossy, green leaves and lavender to violet-colored flowers. It grows in aquatic environments and spreads rapidly.</string>
    <string name="imp_crassipes">Water Hyacinth is a well-known invasive aquatic weed that can have a detrimental impact on rice cultivation. It can obstruct waterways, impede water flow, and reduce sunlight penetration in rice fields. Effective control measures are essential to mitigate its effects.</string>

    <string name="char_stratiotes">Water Lettuce forms rosettes of light green leaves and small white flowers. It is often found in slow-moving water bodies like ponds and freshwater canals.</string>
    <string name="imp_stratiotes">Water Lettuce can be invasive in aquatic environments and may interfere with water management in rice fields if it spreads to irrigation channels or waterways. Proper management practices are needed to control its presence.</string>

    <string name="char_umbelleta">Hydrocotyle umbellata, commonly known as marsh pennywort or dollarweed, exhibits several defining characteristics. Its round to kidney-shaped bright green leaves resemble miniature lily pads, forming low-lying, creeping mats near the ground. Smooth, fleshy stems connect the leaves to the root system, and the plant produces small, inconspicuous flowers in umbrella-like clusters known as umbels. These flowers can be white or greenish-white. Marsh pennywort thrives in moist to wet habitats, including marshes, swamps, and alongside ponds and streams, where it benefits from consistent moisture. With the capacity for both seed reproduction and vegetative propagation, Hydrocotyle umbellata is a persistent and resilient weed. Recognizing these distinctive features is crucial for effective identification and management, particularly in wetland environments.</string>
    <string name="imp_umbelleta" formatted="false">Hydrocotyle umbellata, or marsh pennywort, can impact rice cultivation by competing for essential resources, potentially leading to reduced yields and increased labor for weed management. Its presence in rice fields may also necessitate herbicide use. While it poses challenges for rice farming, this weed contributes to wetland ecosystems biodiversity. Effective weed management is crucial to address these challenges and sustain optimal rice production.</string>


</resources>
